A joint presentation of Persian Geekpedia
and Persia's comics
Persian Geek Pedia
The undertones of the world of comics and cinema
YouTube: Persian Geek Pedia
Telegram: @newpersiangeekpedia
Persia Comics: Everything About Comics and Cinema
Instagram: marvelpersia.ir
YouTube: comicpersia
for a free Iran#
Come on, Drax, dance.
Only idiots dance.
I'm a weirdo.
I wanna have control.
I want a perfect body...
Hey! Uh-uh!
I told you a million times, you keep your
grubby raccoon hands off my Zune!
I told you a million times,
I'm not a damn raccoon.
Again?
I love you, Gamora.
So what are you
gonna do about Quill?
Me? Why not you?
I got emotionalistical issues.
What am I gonna do?
Why are you on the ceiling?
I wanted to see if these new
gravity boots worked on a slope.
Here we go.
Sorry.
(Cosmo speaking Russian)
You must know you will never learn.
You could do better?
Dah.
*
Telekinesis is cheating!
That's a stupid little pebble.
I can do that with my dang finger.
You're a bad dog.
Do not say that to me.
You are. You're a bad dog.
Take that back. Come on,
that's not cool.
Nebula, did you hear?
He called me a bad dog and
he refuse to take it back.
I don't care, Cosmo.
Is Peter okay?
- I don't know.
- What are you going to do?
Me? He's your brother.
It doesn't matter, he still
doesn't listen to me.
Yeah, he has been pretty mopey
ever since Gamora died.
She's not dead.
She just doesn't remember
anything from the past few years.
Nobody tells me nothing.
Mantis, why don't you just touch him?
You know, make him happy.
I am Groot.
Gross!
No, not like that.
Touch him with her powers.
It is wrong to manipulate
the feelings of friends.
What about that time you made
me fall in love with my sock?
Well, that was funny.
I guess it's back to one of us
touching him the other way.
Maybe we should draw straws.
No one ever meant that, Drax.
What was that?!
What the hell?!
Where did you go, Squirrel?
On the ground!
Who is that maniac?
Some super-douche with ray gun hands!
I don't freakin' know.
Who threw this thing at me?
Shut up.
Baby.
Pick on someone your own size.
Peter!
We need med packs.
Nebula.
Piss off!
That hurt.
What a pity.
No!
All I did was activate the med pack!
Get them off! Now!
Oh, hell.
- We need to get him to the med bay.
- It's destroyed.
There's one on the ship!
Stitch him up and transfer
him in with the rest of batch 89.
It's okay.
You're here with us now.
Hey, who's the new guy?
What kind of thing are you?
You've got like, a
mask on your face.
Mask, eyes, face, mouth.
Does it hurts?
It's okay, friend.
Don't let them scare you.
Hurts...
It's okay.
You're gonna be okay.
A kill switch?
A device.
Set to destruct if anyone goes
poking around inside him.
Or even if we use the med packs.
Why would a Rocket
have a kill switch?
Apparently someone considers him proprietary
technology and sent that golden lunatic to get him.
So he'll die if we operate on him?
- And he'll die if we don't.
- There has to be some way to bypass it.
It looks like there's a pass key
that can override the kill switch.
What do we know about
where Rocket came from?
He won't talk about it.
Much of the tech was developed
by a company called Orgocorp.
And there's a code on all of it.
89P13.
He's got maybe 48 hours.
- Where are you going?
- Orgocorp had to have records, right?
Maybe it'll have a way for us to
override the kill switch and save Rocket.
They won't just give us that information.
Well, that's why we're gonna break in.
And kill anyone who gets in our way!
- Not kill anyone.
- Kill a few people.
- Kill no people.
- Kill one guy, one stupid guy who no one loves.
Now you're just making it sad.
Kraglin, Cosmo, I need you to keep watch over
Knowhere till we're back. Couple of days tops.
- Aye, cap'n.
- Aye, comrade.
- Take back what you said that I'm a bad dog.
- Nope.
I know you don't really
think that I'm a bad dog.
- Can you please take it back?
- I will not.
I located the coordinates of Orgocorp.
I think I have a contact near there.
Maybe they can help us get in.
Contact him.
Let's go save our friend.
It's good to have friends.
My poor baby.
Mama, it hurts.
- Do you have it?
- He does not, sire.
I tried to warn you,
High Evolutionary.
These Guardians are more
powerful than you think.
Or perhaps you simply overestimate
your own value, High Priestess.
No doubt, a flaw's on
top of my own design.
I created you lot as merely
an aesthetic experiment.
Beautiful numbskulls.
But your egos have
run wild. Say "ah."
And this one was
meant to be the Warlock.
The apogee of their people.
You removed Adam from
his cocoon early, my liege.
He is still a child.
No, there's something wrong
with him even outside all that.
Yes, there's something wrong with me.
I was stabbed, you extraordinary phallus---
He doesn't know any better. We
shall do whatever you require, my liege.
You knew of 89P13's existence
for years without alerting me.
That's not what I require!
I'm sorry, my liege.
Find 89P13 and return it to me.
Or, I will destroy your entire civilization
as is my right as your maker!
Do you understand?
Yes...
Toodle-loo.
How did 89P13 survive
after all these years, Theel?
It was always clever, sire.
Yes, that's exactly
why I want it now.
- Of course.
- Its brain.
That is the only reason, sire.
But are you really trusting
the Sovereign to retrieve it?
They're merely a backup.
I believe I know where they're going.
It's bioformed.
Instead of being built, it's
grown from living matter.
The structure is surrounded by three
impenetrable plasmic security shields.
It's not gonna be easy to
break into this place, Star-Lord.
Doesn't have to be easy. I was
a professional thief, remember?
I'll jam the signals one at a time.
She calls me Star-Lord
when she's mad at me.
She's always mad at everyone.
It's because I was drunk.
She's right. If I haven't been drinking...
Maybe Rocket... I'm sorry.
It's okay, he's your best friend.
Second best friend.
Everyone around me dies.
My mother, Yondu...
- Gamora...
- Gamora isn't dead.
She is to us.
Do you want a zargnut?
Thank you.
First shield, set.
Three, two, one.
- Peter.
- What?
You had family on Earth. And you
never wanted to go back and see them?
You're my sister. That's all
the family I want or need.
Besides, it's probably just my grandpa,
okay? He was a pretty hard guy.
- Still, don't you think he...
- What?
You were abducted by Ravagers
the same day he lost his daughter.
Oh yeah, he was upset. My mom died, he screamed
at my face and he pushed me out of the room!
He was probably just trying to protect you.
- What are you talking about?
- What?
I'm talking about the people in my life who died,
and you're talking about this?
Second shield, set.
Three, two, one.
I'm only saying you've never
even gone to see if he's okay.
He could still be alive.
My grandpa? He'd be like, 90-
something years old.
So he could still be alive.
People on Earth die
when they're like 50.
They die when they're 50?
I don't know. Something like that.
What's even the
point of being born?
Exactly.
Are you about to die?
I'm not 50!
The point is, I wasn't talking
about any of this.
Third shield, set.
Three, two, one.
Well, not everything is about
what you are talking about.
And I'm only saying you're upset because so
many people you cared about have left you.
But you also left someone.
And maybe I wanted a zargnut.
Too late. They're all gone.
Why didn't we go through?
We did. It's not the shield.
Oh, hell.
Ravagers.
Hey guys, you're about to be
boarded by the United Ravagers.
You can surrender and turn over any stuff
worth anything and live. Or you can die.
It's up to you.
Drax, no, no, no! Drax!
Guys, it's me. Peter Quill.
I'm one of you, remember?
Hold on!
- We have an appointment.
- With who?
- With Gamora.
With Gamora.
What?
You're early.
What are these?
Orgocorp uniforms.
You've got to wear these to move through
the Orgo without attracting attention.
This isn't my color.
What did you say?
It clashes with my eyes.
Put it on!
Nebula, why would you not tell me that
you've been in contact with Gamora?
Because I didn't want
you to get freaked out.
- Freaked... out?!
- Like that.
*
Gamora, we're grateful for your help.
I'm not doing this out of
the kindness of my heart.
I'm doing this for the hundred
thousand units my sister promised.
So you're a Ravager now?
Put on the uniform.
Never pictured you as the Ravager type.
Who are you again?
Oh, man...
OrgoCorp is in possession of some of the
most advanced cybergenetic IP in the galaxy.
So they're heavily guarded
by the deadly Orgosentries.
Now I know you don't have
documentation to dock.
So you're gonna have to
get in there on your own.
Once in, Gamora is gonna
lead you to the records.
Where maybe you can find the
pass key to override the kill switch.
And help you save the hedgehog.
But if you get into trouble,
we will not be able
to bail you out.
Yes.
Yes, of course.
Its functioning has skyrocketed.
That's correct, P13. Very good.
That's the new world.
Counter-Earth.
Where the experiments will
go once they're ready.
- It blue.
- That's the sky.
Sky.
- Rocket.
- Yes, it is.
What sounds?
That's music.
- We like it?
- We do.
This recording is over 5,000 years old.
Which translated, is...
Be not as you are,
but as you should be.
It's our sacred mission
to take the cacophony
of sounds around us
and turn it into a song.
To take an imperfect clump of
biological matter such as you,
and transform it into something...
perfect.
And we're halfway there, aren't we?
Come with me, P13.
I'd like to show you something.
We have but a single quest...
To create the perfect species,
and the perfect society.
You, P13,
are part of batch 89.
But here, with batch 90,
I've developed a process
by which I can guide
any organism through millions of years of
programmed evolution changes, in a moment.
See now...
There's the rub.
For some reason, these specimens
are also over producing the legobeta
microsamino protein in their systems.
Causing them to be, well...
Violent. We don't like it.
A utopia cannot have its denizens
murdering one another, can it?
They can't.
- Can't.
Theel.
They're programmed to be peaceful, like you.
But for some reason, it's not catching.
Tectonic filters.
What?
They suppresaliding the glycusoride sources.
And then, boop, boop, boop...
Absisting residual deformity.
And then, they, make, um...
- What do you say?
- The legobeta Microsamino proteins.
Yeah, thems.
And then, angry turtleses.
There, that's the decompression chamber.
Lock in.
Go.
Activate gravity boots and gloves.
Nebula, go.
So you really don't remember anything?
Like what?
- Bunch of time with us.
- No.
- Well, we were...
- We weren't anything.
- You and me...
- That was some alternate future version of me.
Wasn't me.
We loved each other.
I don't think so.
I know you don't remember any of it...
You were everything to me.
I miss you.
So much.
And maybe...
Maybe if you open yourself up to it...
- There's a possibility...
- I don't think so, Quinn.
- Quill.
I don't think so.
But what I'm trying to say...
Peter, you know this
is an open line, right?
- What?
- We're listening to everything you're saying.
And it is painful.
And you're just telling me now?
We were hoping it
would stall on its own.
But I switched it over to private.
What color button did you push?
Blue. For the blue suit.
- Oh, no.
- Blue is the open line for everyone.
Orange is for blue.
- What?
- Black is for orange.
Yellow is for green.
Green is for red.
And red is for yellow.
No, yellow is for yellow.
Green is for red.
Red is for green.
- I don't think so.
- Try it, then.
Hello!
- You were right.
- How the hell am I supposed to know all of that!?
Seems intuitive.
Can we get back to saving our friend?
Get that jammer ready
to change the shield.
Guys?
You wanna talk about a sweet ride?
The acceleration would crush your spine.
It's got that brand new Fusilux core.
You know what I'm talking about?
- Oh, yeah.
- Really? Because I just made that up.
Oh, I thought you
said something else.
Master Karja.
- No, you didn't.
- I did... I did.
Master Karja, there appears to be a physical
breach in the white wing somewhere.
Could it be a glitch?
Maybe?
I'm accessing the eye.
I'll see if I can locate it.
There's some sort of anomaly in the decompression
chamber. Best to check it out, Master.
On it.
Hurry.
Where do we put these?
Here! Hide them in this
locker until we leave.
Hurry.
What the hell was that, guys?
Are you kidding me?
- What?
- A neutral cork just hit the satellite.
It's burning a hole thru the wall. You geniuses just
throw the door open without any precautionary procedure?
What procedure, bro?
Oh, you want us to read the
manual for you too, bro?
You could have killed everyone in the wing.
Exactly, you idiots!
I'm angry, too.
Oh, no.
Can't you see these authentic mechanic
uniforms we're wearing on our bodies?
That blend in with some of our
skin tones better than others?
Excuse my friend. He's the
boss' nephew. He's a little...
Oh...
Oh.
Yeah, I...
I got one of those too.
This one? This one, I love.
I'm so proud of...
You're doing great.
So proud of you.
But this one...
I just...
Everything he does drives me crazy.
- I thought you said something else.
- Shut up.
I swear I'm gonna throttle him.
I'm gonna go to jail for murder.
I am.
How did you guys get here so fast?
Gonna be honest with you, we just happened
in before it burned all the way through, thankfully.
Good thing you were here.
Alright guys, wrap it up.
Looks like we're all clear here.
Our spacesuits!
You threw them in the contamination bin.
It expels stuff into space the
moment you shut the door.
That would have been helpful
information three minutes ago!
Dammit, Mantis, why don't you ever think?
Oh, are we pretending
to be angry again?
Mantis, you asshole!
Guys, just focus for two seconds.
We'll find another way
out of here. Right now...
We need to save Rocket's life.
Nebula, Quinn and I will get to
the records and get the pass key.
Bug and doufus, access the spaceport thru the
elevator so Tree can land and get us out of here.
- Oh, apologies.
- No problem.
Go.
It's not my fault I don't know what
something is. No one ever tells me.
I didn't even want to come here.
I'm gonna need to see your...
You're hopelessly in love... with him.
Oh, no...
- Hey.
How are you doing today?
I'm alright.
What was your name again?
Drax the Destroyer.
That's such a lovely name.
I'll get the door for you.
- I'll be here when you come back out, okay?
- Sure.
Every single time.
My name is Brittle Snorte!
Welcome to OrgoCorp headquarters.
For over 300 years OrgoCorp has been producing cybernetic
implants and genetic upgrades across the universe.
Under the watchful eye
of the High Evolutionary.
That warning we got today. Don't
those two match the description?
Attention all Orgosentries.
That manager should
have access to the records.
If the pass key is here,
she can get it for us.
All right.
- I'll handle this one.
- How?
Pure Star-Lord charm.
I'm excited that you get to see
this again for the first time.
Hi, Yura.
- Ura.
- Oh, Ura.
- Hi.
- Hi, my name is Patrick Swayze.
I've been noticing you
for quite a while.
And whenever you smile to yourself,
when you think nobody is looking,
it makes my everyday a bit brighter.
We need your hand, and it's your choice
whether it's on your body, or not!
What are you doing?
She was never gonna fall for that.
She was totally into me, man.
I kinda thought you
were a douchebag.
Oh, come on.
- We need a file.
- What file?
89P13. Would that be something?
- No.
- Then your use to us is over.
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait!
Sounds like a species tag.
Show us!
All of our research supports the High
Evolutionary's altruistic objective,
of creating a utopian society.
That must be the spaceport.
Whoa.
What is all this?
Species patented over the
years using OrgoCorp tech.
Every species Orgocorp has created
has its own individual file.
I am so sorry about this. Listen to me,
this is not the kinda thing we do.
Oh, please, stop it
with the subtle jabs!
Old you would've never done this.
You had a purpose higher than
yourself, the calling to help people.
That's why you left Thanos
and formed the Guardians.
Except I didn't form the Guardians
and I barely left Thanos.
Whoever it was that
you were in love with,
it wasn't me.
It sounds more like her.
- Her?
- What?
- That's ridiculous...
- Do not drag me into this.
- Knock it off!
- What?
Don't look at me like a lost puppy
needing a safe place to lie down!
I didn't say anything.
I just never noticed how
black your eyes were.
They were replaced by my father
as a method of torture.
He picked a pretty set.
There.
That's the file for 89P13.
Oh, no.
Walk!
Run, run.
Stand down!
Drax, we should make a run for it.
- Or we can fight.
- Run.
- Fight.
- Run!
- Fight!
- Take 'em!
What are we going to do?
- I got a plan.
- What is it?
All of you, come with---
Everybody, lower your weapons or
I blow this woman's brain out!
That's the plan?
You're a kitty cat.
You feel like dancing.
Violent rage.
Lower your weapons!
Now kill that one that looks like a
carrot to show we mean business.
God! Past Gamora's just mean!
She was always like that,
and yet I was the bad guy.
We are not killing anyone!
Back off!
Groot, bring the Bowie to us. Now!
- I'm so sorry about this, Ura.
- Oh, please.
We're here to save the
life of our friend. That is all.
We paid her to help
us get in and get out.
You'd think that'd mean, "oh, I'm gonna help them do
it in a way that no one knows what's happening."
But no. What she means is I'm gonna
shoot people. Threaten people's lives.
Shut up!
And now I know you're probably
asking "why would I trust her?" Well...
That's a good question.
The answer is...
We used to be in love.
Yeah, she was my girlfriend. Only she
doesn't remember it because it wasn't her.
Because her dad threw her off a magic cliff and she died.
Then I lost my temper and nearly destroyed half the universe.
And she came back.
Out of the past. There she is.
Anyone else who died in the past stayed dead.
Not her. Why? Was it the magic cliff? I don't know.
I'm not some freakin'
Infinity Stone scientist.
Just some dumbass Earth dude
who met a girl, fell in love.
That girl died,
and then came
back a total dick.
You left out some important
information, but...
That is the gist of it.
Get to the security helm.
Okay!
Everybody down on the floor
or we blow your brains out.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
We don't want any---
Come on! Will you please
stop doing that?
Hey!
Run.
Drax!
Get on the ground, and
show me your hands now.
Ura...
Please listen to me. We need
to get out of here with this.
To save my best friend's life.
If you can get us into the systems of those
sentries out there, they are good people, like you...
I'm certain of it.
And if I just had an
opportunity to speak to them...
They're corporate shills, you idiot.
They're not gonna listen.
They will listen if I speak
to them from my heart.
Ura...
please.
Hey!
Come out now!
Damn it!
Stop!
You are in.
- Tell them your truce---
- Yeah, I'm not that big of an idiot.
I just needed to get
into the system.
Told you she was into me.
I am Groot.
Yeah. That looked cool.
Is sky?
No.
That's not sky. That's a ceiling.
Sire is making a
new world for all of us.
And when we get there,
there will be sky,
and it will be beautiful.
And forever.
I have been thinking.
About what?
Oh, nothing in particular.
But I thought, since you
guys are my closest friends,
and my only friends,
you might be interested in knowing
that I have been thinking.
That's cool.
I've been thinking, too.
About something more singular.
When sire moves
us to the new world,
we're gonna need names.
I mean, 89Q12...
Not really a name.
So...
I would like my name to be...
Lylla.
That's a pretty name, Lylla.
Thank you.
I think my name shall be Teefs.
Because although
we all do have them,
mine are definitely
the most prominent.
- Teefs.
- Lylla.
Me be called Floor...
Because me is lying on floor.
You're lying on a floor,
so your name is Floor?
Yeah.
Floor.
What about you, friend?
Someday, I'm gonna make
great machines that fly.
And me and my friends are
going to go flying together.
Into the forever
and beautiful sky.
Lylla, and Teefs, and Floor...
And me.
Rocket.
It really is good to have friends.
Yeah.
Start the incision here.
Keep calm.
- Hold it still.
- I can't. It won't stop moving!
Why did he never tell
us about any of this?
This is worse than what
Thanos did to me.
But what about the pass key?
Is it there?
No. But a file was
removed today.
Downloaded and deleted a
million characters at length.
The biometrics say
it was this man.
Recorder B2H6.
I saw this guy outside
of records today.
Looks like one of the
High Evolutionary's recorders.
The High Evolutionary?
The founder of OrgoCorp?
OrgoCorp is just a way to fund his
experiments that lie outside intergalactic laws.
He's created whole societies.
Xeronians, the Animen.
- Sovereign.
- The Sovereign?
Corners of the universe
consider him god.
- I am Groot.
- Yes.
Yes, what? That he's Groot?
He said maybe this man downloaded the
pass key into the computer on his head.
Huh?
That can store the pass key.
If we find him, we save Rocket.
The High Evolutionary's coordinates.
Put the coordinates in the nav.
Wait a minute.
Are you kidding me?
What he wants is that
gutted badger in the med bay.
And you're gonna bring
it straight to him?
It's almost certainly a trap.
A trap isn't a trap if you know the trap
is trying to trap you. It's a face-off.
A face-off is a trap
if you're facing off against a guy a thousand
times more powerful than you.
Do you know who
the High Evolutionary is?
Yeah, he's some dickhead who
dissected my best friend.
Second best.
The High Evolutionary isn't someone
you wanna think about messing with.
We won't think about
it when we do it.
You know what? I don't care.
Just drop me off with the Ravagers and
you go do whatever it is you wanna do.
We don't have time for this.
I'm not asking you. Drop me
off with my people now.
Your people?
The Ravagers aren't your people.
I'm a damn Ravager. You aren't.
Listen, I know you were always
looking for a family, okay?
But my Gamora, the one I loved, she
didn't find it with a group of criminals.
She found it with us.
People who care about you.
I know that's who you still are.
Somewhere inside of you...
What are you so afraid of in yourself,
that I need to be something for you?
I don't give a shit
about your Gamora!
Life made me me!
I have a few upgrades courtesy of
that gutted badger in the med bay.
And we are not risking his life
to make yours more convenient.
- I'm family.
- So is he.
Screw you.
Screw all of you.
Found him on the outskirts
of the first shield,
pirating supply ships.
I do appreciate this, good sir.
And I appreciate your contribution
to the Orgosentry retirement fund.
Your associate.
A Zehoberi named Gamora.
- Where is she now.
- You'll get nothing from me!
Oh, we'll see about
that, won't we?
Adam.
Adam!
- Yes, mother.
- Show him we mean business.
I said show him we mean business!
Not disintegrate him!
Well, what business could
we have shown him?
But now he is
of no use to us!
Well let's just question the man's friend!
Friend? You think that's
a friend? It's an animal!
He looks sad.
I really don't enjoy how that's
making me feel, actually.
Your friend's a moron. I got
one of those, too. I get it.
Outpost?
This is Gamora. Are you there?
If you can pick this up, come in.
Outpost, come in.
Yes, Gamora.
Salutations.
May I help?
Well, I need you guys
to come pick me up.
I'm gonna upload the location
link to the craft I'm on.
Oh, I think we can arrange that.
You need to say to him exactly
what I told you to say.
Why don't you just say it?
No one ever listens to me.
Quill.
Life is a pond.
And you spent your entire life leaping from woman
to woman, as if they are lily pads upon this great pond.
Perhaps what you need to do, Quill...
... is learn to swim.
- That actually made sense.
- Yes it made sense.
No, I mean, 'cause that's
sort of an analogy.
I didn't know that you were
capable of that... I thought...
I know lots of analogies, Quill.
Analogies, metaphors, etcetera?
For instance...
Gamora's head is like a lily pad.
Because it's green.
Analogy.
And also, stupid-looking and flappy.
- Flappy?
- Because her skin is made of leaf.
- Metaphor.
- Is it?
Yesterday, I made a poop
shaped like a fish.
Even my butt, is capable
of making an analogy.
Oh.
What's happening?
The fluid is in his lungs.
P13!
Sire.
Sire was in the middle of his treatment,
soon we had a breakthrough with that tube.
Perhaps then we should resume tomorrow...
We will not resume tomorrow, no!
P13
Oh, ooh, there you are.
Hello.
How did you know about
the microsamino proteins, P13?
What happened in there?
Why?
How did you know, P13?
It was too little filtration.
In the hyperthermic, yes, we know.
We fixed that.
But how did you know?
I made you!
How did you know!?
Because it worked.
It worked...
The rage, is gone.
We have the peaceful creatures
we always sought...
Ready to inhabit the new world.
We're going to the new world?
Oh... we?
Look at you.
It's if you were cobbled
together by fat-fingered children.
How could you be part
of a perfect species?
You're simply a...
medley of mistakes we could learn from in
the plight of the creatures that truly matter.
Batch 89...
was never meant for
the new world, P13.
You could figure out the complex workings
of cytoplasmic filtration systems,
but you couldn't figure out that?
But that brain...
That, I'd like to study further.
Prep it for surgery and
removal in the morning.
What about the rest
of batch 89, sire?
Incinerate them.
He's dying. We need that pass key.
We don't have long.
We've arrived.
That looks just like... home.
It's like a replica of Earth.
It makes no sense.
Atmosphere is habitable.
Gravity is and/or minus one.
Hello. We mean
you no harm.
Listen to me, he was just trying
to throw her back the ball.
Please, no...
Hey! Hey.
Groot! Full kaiju!
- Not full kaiju!
- I am Groooooot!
Get down, Groot!
Everybody, it's okay.
Hey.
Hi. We're not here to harm you.
Okay... you see?
For your knee.
We just need to
save our friend.
It doesn't belong here.
I will train it in the
ways of the Sovereign.
I will train him not to do that.
The blasphemy
even having it here.
Kill it! Now.
I'm the Warlock, mum, and I'm
done of being ordered around.
Gamora is here.
Which means the squirrel is, also...
To save ourselves, we must bring it to the
High Evolutionary before his own people do.
Yeah, yeah. Sit. Let's sit.
Okay.
I am Groot.
It's not rude, it's what it's here for.
Drax, sit up! Idiot.
Thank you.
Our friend,
he's dying.
We love our friend.
But he is dying.
That's not dying.
That's already dead.
They'll think he's already dead.
They'll think we are
here on a quest for revenge.
Drax, sit up!
- That's what it's here for.
- Drax, it isn't.
It's made for people to sit shoulder to shoulder right
next to each other. Get your boots off their pillows.
I find it hard to believe it doesn't
have a multiple purpose.
I'm sorry. My friend is a dumbass.
That's the same as your dying.
Why do you criticize everything?
So why is the couch long then?
It was a totally different sound.
No it isn't. Ugh! Dying... ugh!
Dumbass... see? It's the same.
Alright, guys. Can I proceed, please?
We're trying to save our friend.
Drax, I see you.
I understand that none of this
makes any sense to you right now.
We need your help
in finding a man.
I'm gonna draw. I'm gonna draw
the man that we're looking for.
You see the thing on her head?
He has a thing...
That is delightful.
There you go.
Have you seen this man?
That's very good.
Can I have that later to hang
on my apartment, please?
Yeah, thank you.
His name? His name is Motio?
Many Motios. There?
That pyramid?
Is that your car
in the driveway?
Drax, stay here with Rocket.
Watch him, that's who
they're coming for.
- I want to come!
- No.
Mantis, watch Drax.
Groot, you know what
to do with these.
Push down on it.
- What?
- Push it down.
I am pushing down on it.
Push the button.
Looks like you're pushing the keyhole.
- What?
- There's a button under the handle.
Press that in.
Okay. Now what?
Open the fucking door!
That is a stupid design.
And the instructions
were very unclear!
Let's get that pass key
and save our friend.
I was 8 years old when I left Earth, okay? Why would
I know any more about driving one of these than you do?
Don't say you're volunteering.
- You want me to drive? I'll drive.
- No!
I don't want you
to drive. I got this.
You must be
a really loyal pet
if they're willing to
do all this for you.
This is the perfect society?
Sire...
This one has been running for two
hours without breaking a sweat.
That's incredible, if I...
They can survive on 30 calories a day and
half of sleep a week. They are always happy.
And they can rewire a carbonetrix
core in under two minutes.
But will she be ready
for the new colony?
Sire, they're here.
Here we go.
- We're here to see...
- The High Evolutionary's expecting you.
Which means it is a trap.
It's a face-off.
She stays here.
- Why?
- Policy against weaponry.
And your arm is a gun.
- He's clean.
- Let's go.
Hey.
It'll be okay.
Move it!
Are you okay, Rocket?
Me and Rocket play now?
I can't right now, Floor.
- What are you doing?
- They ain't gonna set us free.
Yes they are, Rocket. We're going
to the new world any day now.
No, that can't be true.
It is.
They wanna kill
us all in the morning.
- What?
But I'm gonna fix it.
What is that?
It's a key.
I'm gonna use it to
get us all outta here.
I don't know if
that's wise, Rocket.
Me, Rocket, leave!
Hurray, friends forever!
Just down that hall,
there's ships.
I know that if we can
get to one, I can pilot it.
And then we'll all
fly away together.
The four of us, just like
we always said, okay?
Okay?
Woohoo! Yippee, Rocket!
Sky, sky, sky!
You did it!
It really is good to have---
Yes, I imagined you'd
do something like this.
Back in the cage, P13.
Sky...
Rocket, Teefs, Floor go now!
Q12 and P13 escaped
from their pens.
Q12 is neutralized, but...
P13 is still out,
so I'll need assistance.
Rocket, Teefs, Floor go now!
Remember, not
to bruise its brain.
Alright, P13!
You win the crying contest,
now back in the cage!
Rocket, Teefs, Floor go now!
Just go! Rocket, please!
Rocket! Rocket!
Down here, hurry!
What are you doing?
I have a bad feeling about this.
Peter just told you to stay here.
Yeah well, that's his fault.
He should know by now that I never
do anything that anyone ever tells me.
We need to protect Rocket.
Yeah, that's right.
So hop on. And we'll
ride back to the ship.
Just right over there?
Yeah.
Drax! Hey, stop being a jerk.
You! Hey! Yeah, you.
I take it the pass key, it's in
that thing on your head.
I would advise
against aggression.
Oh, got time for me now?
Your friend once took advantage.
I learned my lessons.
I aimed some small part of my mental
capacity back in my own direction.
And now, gravity itself
serves my whims.
War Pig, now.
You must find Counter-Earth familiar.
- Counter-Earth.
- I visited your planet many years ago.
Earth hasn't been my
planet in a long time.
Your people had...
Wonderful spirit.
The art, music and literature,
were some of the
finest in the universe.
Earth would be a fabulous place were
it not for the ignorance and bigotry.
- Okay.
- It inspired me to create Counter-Earth.
- I don't care...
- All of the good and none of the bad.
I don't need another speech
by some impotent whackjob
whose mother didn't love him, rationalizing
why he needs to conquer the universe.
I'm not trying to
conquer the universe...
I'm perfecting it.
What the...
Hey!
Drop the badger.
I just want the pass key.
Then bring me 89P13.
I am Groot.
He says suck my---
Why are you so angry?
Because I know what
you did to our friend.
Anything I've done, I've done for
the betterment of the universe.
Newsflash, Einstein. Better universe generally don't include
a bunch of octopuses selling meth to guys with cockroach heads.
They do not.
Which is why, as I've
done many times before...
I'm going to have to raze it all,
and start again.
I got 89P13 and
I'm on my way.
We're in possession of the subject.
Oh, my God.
I am Groot?
Kill them all.
Stay.
I said stay.
What? Did you want me to leave you
back so that mother could pull at you?
Stay.
What the hell, we're working
for the same boss.
Yes, but I need the credit, chum.
To save my entire civilization.
So be a good creepy... thing,
and back off.
Oh.
Mother.
Mother!
Mantis, Drax, come in.
Mantis, Drax?
- Uh, hey.
- I need you to bring the ship here, now!
Well, we can't do that exactly, because...
We're not in the ship.
Then where the hell are you?
- Nebula, come in.
- Gamora!
Take off now! Get yourself
and Rocket off the planet!
What kind of ship is this?
That's amusing, really.
How stupid are you?
It was so obviously a trap.
It's not a trap, it's a face-off!
Now, kill them all.
Grenade!
I am Groot!
No, no, no, please.
*
Thank you, thank you.
That would be premature.
Huh? No, no, no, no!
Quite a novel escape plan.
Jumping headfirst into
an exploding planet.
You'll kill us both!
Not both!
Why are we doing this?
Quill and Groot are inside!
We have to get them out.
Groot.
Whoever's in the cockpit,
activate the brake.
The steering mechanism is stuck!
Well, pull harder!
Let's go!
It's hard to breathe.
We are entering space.
Oh, piss off.
What kind of monster
slaughters a civilization?
- Where are Mantis and Drax?
- I do not know!
You're lucky I was able
to knock down that door.
Rocket and Gamora, are
probably dead because of you!
- I didn't know.
- Oh, you didn't know?
When are you gonna stop using the
excuse of being some big dumb clown
for contributing nothing, and the
rest of us having to carry your slack!
Don't push him! You don't have
the right to push him.
And you, you're no better.
The only thing we can count on you for, is when someone
shows weakness, you'll be right there to support it.
Fine, I don't care.
I know you need to find fault in everyone
else to make yourself feel okay.
So find it in me.
Go to hell, Mant!
But you don't have
the right to push him!
It's not his fault he's stupid.
He's a liability.
He makes us laugh and he loves
us. How is that a liability?
All you care about is
intelligence and competence.
Not sure I appreciate this defense.
He has sadness...
But he's the only one of you
who doesn't hate himself.
I don't care if he's stupid.
Do you think I'm stupid?
Yes.
Forget.
Hah! You're lucky I was able to knock
down that door with my incredible strength.
Quill?
Quill, are you there?
This language isn't in my translator.
Okay.
Alright, Rocket. Go.
Lylla?
Friend.
Okay. Okay...
Okay, here we go.
This isn't right.
No, no, no. It's good.
It's gonna work. It's working.
It needs to be faster.
I'm sorry, I'm so sorry.
- Rocket.
- I let you down.
I got you killed.
You were right.
The sky is beautiful.
And it is forever.
And I've been flying
with our friends.
Can I come?
Yes.
No, no, no, no.
No!
- Come on!
- Quill.
No!
- Quill...
- No!
- I'm not gonna lose him.
- He is gone.
I'm not letting him go!
But not yet.
You still have a purpose here.
A purpose for what?
They made us for nothing!
Just a bunch of experiments
to be thrown away!
There are the hands that made us...
and then there are the
hands that guide the hands.
My beloved raccoon...
This story has been yours
all along. You just didn't know it.
I'm not a raccoon.
The pass key's coming through!
Where's Nebula?
She, she's, uh....
'Cause her call's on
the comm behind you.
- What... Nebula?
- Where are you?
- Oh, thank God!
- We're here to get you out of here.
- Out of where?
- The High Evolutionary's ship!
No, I got off the ship.
- You what?
- Wait, where are you?
On the ship!
- On the ship?!
- I didn't lie.
- Why are you on the ship?
- To save you, obviously!
No, I told you to go back. You gotta know by now I
always figure out a clever way to get out of a fix!
- Tell him I said hi.
- Really?
Tell him we're coming to save him.
Pay attention or play with
the kids. One or the other.
- Play with the kids?
- How did you get out?
- That's not really important...
- I am Groot.
Jumping a 1000 feet to your death without a
parachute is a clever way of getting out of a fix?
You're only just making up
stuff that he's saying, right?
The important thing
is we're all okay.
Rocket?
Yes, he's here and he's okay.
Rocket, we love you very much
and we're happy you're alive.
Well that makes you idiots, then.
He's right about that.
Back in your cages!
Nebula?
Nebula, come in.
So, you'd like to joust, would you?
Go to hell, you sick
son of a bitch.
You killed all of those people.
As I will your friends.
I'm sending you the coordinates.
They will die unless you
bring me what is mine!
Screw you, you stretch-faced, Robocop looking,
Skeletor wannabe, purple-nurple, piece of---
He hung up.
You think?
1966...
The Soviets put me on a rocket
knowing full well I never to return
and I will die in a fiery ball of death.
The one thing even Soviets never do,
is call me "bad dog."
Oh, my God, just let it go.
Kraglin, please, just take it back.
This is killing us.
I can't take it back if she
is, in fact, a bad dog.
It never stops hurting.
- Kraglin.
- Oh, hey, Pete.
We need to save
Nebula, Mantis and Drax,
and we need your help.
Me?
You're the one who
lost him, you twit!
The hellspawn heard it, sire.
- But...
- But, but, but, but, but!
That rancid word.
I'm merely wondering
whether it might be wiser,
to go directly to the new colony and
not engage in unnecessary conflict.
They can rewire a carbonetrix
core in under two minutes.
But what is that, Vim?
- Rote memorization.
- Rote memorization!
In hundreds of years of our creations,
only one has known true invention.
One.
Putrid in every other way,
but 89P13 had that.
Yes, sire.
A populace unable to think,
what hasn't yet been thought, will die.
And why we need 89P13's brain
so we can transfer that
trait into these creatures
before we go to the new colony.
Nothing else matters.
How did they get down here?
Peter will be trying to
get to the spaceport.
He doesn't know about the children.
You!
We need you to let all the other children onboard
know to stay away from the starboard walls!
They know three freaking words
and two of them are joob.
No! Listen to me.
You need to talk
to the other children.
All of them here, and tell them,
to stay away, from the freakin'----
What the hell are you
doing, Mantis?
Explaining it, dickhead!
You're scaring them.
Hello, dumb idiots.
I had a little girl like you.
You know what she used to like?
She liked when I
made monkey noises.
How is that a monkey?
Beats me.
They're gonna tell the other kids to stay
away from the starboard wall.
Why didn't you tell us you knew
their language this whole time?
Why didn't you ask?
This could be futile, Quill.
He's too powerful.
Well then, I guess we'll die trying.
What is dying trying gonna accomplish?
Or we can just give
him the badger.
Our thing, is dying trying.
I am Groot.
I know who you are already!
Feel free to stay
behind in the cargo area.
I'm not leaving my
sister with that jackass.
This you?
Fell out of your bag.
Let's do this.
Wait...
You almost have to
admire their pluck.
Sire.
Howdy there, you freakin' creep.
- Back up!
- Yes, sire.
You're on, Steemie.
First barrel.
Second barrel.
Third barrel.
Fourth barrel.
Hard starboard.
And, fire!
They've breached the spaceport.
One of them holds subject 89P13.
Release the hellspawn, all of them.
Sire, the hellspawn were created
solely to defend the new colony.
Do it now!
Get me 89P13,
and kill everyone in the
head of that dead god!
Spaceport wide open, Cap'n, but
that armaments was all we had.
Rocket, Groot, go, go!
Get inside that spaceport.
What the hell?
Aww, come on!
Kraglin, we have been infiltrated!
Open the pit.
Sire, our bargaining
power will be gone.
Abilisks!
Good God...
This way!
One more step and
this weird thing gets it!
Don't be rash.
What were you programming?
Self-destruction code.
What are you doing?
It's okay.
Mantis, stop.
They eat batteries, not people.
Maybe they're just scared of
what we are gonna do to them.
We're not gonna hurt you.
Everything is going to be okay.
Use your heart, boy.
A dog?
Yeah.
She's a good dog.
I knew you believe
I'm good dog.
Alright, alright,
alright. Get off me.
Sire, we must retreat.
The ship is going down.
The spaceport has intruders.
Go, see if one of them is 89P13.
Sire, you have an irrational
obsession with this animal.
You must stop
for God's sake---
There is no god!
That's why I stepped in!
Controller, I am taking
command of the Arete.
Disengage all damaged
sectors of the ship.
And retreat...
Attention,
all personnel...
Intruders have boarded the ship.
Head to the starboard spaceport.
Bring me 89P13.
And kill the rest.
We go in there, we get
Mantis, Nebula and Drax.
We move in, we get
them, and get out.
Did that look cool?
Okay.
New gameplan. We get
the hell outta here now.
There are thousands of
creatures on this ship.
- Many of them are children.
- We need to be good joob-joob.
- Huh?
- It means friends.
If we want to live,
we have to leave now.
This whole rig is gonna
go down any second.
They will all die, if
we don't help them.
I'm done runnin'.
There's a big hole
up in the deck.
If we can connect that to Knowhere,
we can lead the survivors to safety.
Nebs and me
will pilot the ship.
You guys save all
the higher life forms.
Hello, moron.
Come on!
Follow me, come on!
Go, go, go!
I am Groot.
Um, this way to...
Thank you.
Yes, you're welcome.
I was screaming at something
scary behind you. Not you.
You look really cool.
Kill me if you want, but then
good luck getting out of here.
Let him go. That guy's
our only chance.
I got a space big enough to get through. I gotta
find out if I can change it to a permeable shield.
I can't fly this freakin' thing. The
controls are all screwed.
I'll do it.
Go help the others. Wait,
give me your comm.
Kraglin, I'll pilot
from this side.
Nebula, back in action.
Come on, come on, come on!
Go, go!
Go, go, go!
Wait, wait. Wait, wait, wait.
Stop, stop!
Are those kids?
Okay, Cosmo, stitch it up.
It needs to be airtight for
the kids to make it across!
Locking up, captain.
Go, now, go.
One by one.
Landing in, and headed down.
This way, this way.
Why?
Why are you doing this?
I tried to kill you.
I am Groot.
He says everyone
deserves a second chance.
You are so strong.
Come on! Why
are you so slow?
Where is Rocket?
No!
You thought you could escape me?
You think you have some worth in
and of yourself without me?
No!
You are an abomination!
Nothing more than a step, on my path!
You freakish little monster!
How dare you think you are more?
8-9-P-1-3!
The name's Rocket.
Rocket Raccoon.
His face came off.
It's a mask.
Look what you did to me.
For what?
All I wanted to do...
was to make things perfect.
You didn't want to
make things perfect.
You just hated things
the way they are.
Kill him.
Why?
Because I'm a freakin'
Guardian of the Galaxy.
We have to get
out of here, now.
We have to save them
We've got all the kids on board.
No, Pete. The
rest of them.
Come on! Come on, move.
Move it.
Whoa.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
I thought we were limiting ourselves
to the higher life forms.
Me, too.
Go babies. Go, babies.
Go!
I cannot hold... much...
Quill!
Hurry!
Peter!
Peter.
Did that...
... look cool?
Come on.
Cosmo.
I'm okay.
I am Groot.
Thanks, just tell them
I'm gonna be right...
I am Groot.
Yeah. It's good working
with you too.
Hey Gamora, are you ready?
Yeah.
You know I'm still not
who you want me to be.
I know.
But who you are ain't so bad.
I bet we were fun.
Like you wouldn't believe.
All right.
Are you okay?
I think I need to
talk to everybody.
So, you're gonna leave?
My mother died in front of me when I was 8
years old and I have been running ever since.
I'm gonna need to take some time.
Learn how to swim.
I as well.
I love you all.
I do.
But my whole life, I did
whatever Ego wanted.
And then I did whatever
the Guardians wanted.
I need to go out and
discover what I want.
- I will come with you.
- No Drax.
That's the whole point.
But you need someone to protect you.
- I don't.
- Not in a bad way.
Just because of your
incredible weakness.
Oh, my God, you're so frustrating.
Drax, I need you here.
We're building a new society.
I need all the support I can get
for those children out there.
Today, I saw who you are.
You weren't born
to be a destroyer.
You were born
to be a dad.
So you'll lead the Guardians then?
No.
I'm going to lead the city.
Make it the type of
home I never had.
So that's it?
The group's over?
No.
The galaxy still
needs its guardians.
And you, will make a better
leader than I ever was...
Captain.
I love you, guys.
Welcome home.
I think I might
be at the wrong...
I'm looking for Jason Quill?
Yes. Come in.
Pete.
Hi, Grandpa.
A joint presentation of Persian Geekpedia
and Persia's comics
Persia Comics: Everything About Comics and Cinema
Instagram: marvelpersia.ir
YouTube: comicpersia
Persian Geek Pedia
The undertones of the world of comics and cinema
YouTube: Persian Geek Pedia
Telegram: @newpersiangeekpedia
Okay, how about your
favorite musical act?
Phyla, you first.
Britney Spears and Korn.
- Good choices.
- I gotta go with the man.
Garth Brooks.
The Carpenters did not
have a single bad song.
Adrian Belew.
Both solo, and his work
with King Crimson.
What about you, captain?
Oh, this one's kinda special.
come and get your love
Guess they're here.
Well...
I can handle this by my lonesome
if you all wanna chill.
Nah, nah, it'll go fast if
we all do it together.
Groot, wake up.
Does anyone feel a
little sad for them?
Yeah, sure. But these townsfolk
can't protect themselves.
On your word, Captain.
Word.
If she needs help mowing the lawn, I'll
do it but it kinda feel like her son's job.
Is she gonna sit on the
porch and watch me do it?
Like, a 45 year old man,
quietly mowing his lawn...
It just feels weird.
Don't get me started.
All right?
I kinda wanna know.
translation: FujiFilm69